<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://shlee-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://shlee-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-07-05T02:02:35+00:00</updated><id>https://shlee-lab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Suhyeon Lee</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">My trip to Tallinn</title><link href="https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/trip-in-Tallinn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My trip to Tallinn"/><published>2023-06-15T19:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-15T19:53:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/trip-in-Tallinn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/trip-in-Tallinn/"><![CDATA[<p>Where do you think of when you visit Tallinn, Estonia? It is an old town with a beautiful medieval appearance. However, Old Town is not the place where the Estonians lived.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-1-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-1-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-1-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tallinn-1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Tallinn's old town entrance. </div> <p>According to the locals, this is where the Germans lived, who owned the Estonians who were serfs. Estonians are said to have lived outside the walls in very shabby places like thatched houses. Old Town has a medieval atmosphere and is well-managed, so I took a look around and left for where the Estonians lived.</p> <p>See the below two photos. The place I visited where the Estonians lived is a residential complex built during the Soviet era. Estonia was communist and annexed by the Soviet Union, and it had an independent history in 1991. In this place, you could see three to five stories of apartments that looked like matchboxes. Most of the exterior is not properly maintained. I could see paint peeling everywhere. It is said that what is more serious than the appearance is the inside. There were also buildings with high floors or slightly colorful exterior decorations, which are said to have been built during the Stalin era. It is said that it was built to look splendid to show the excellence of communism, but only the outside looks good and the inside is seriously bad.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-2-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-2-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-2-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tallinn-2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-3-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-3-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/tallinn-3-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/tallinn-3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Apartments built in the Soviet era. </div> <p>In particular, buildings built after the mid-Soviet era were often stolen by people during construction. So, especially those who are “allocated” on the upper floor of the apartment building are completely ruined, but there are no pipes that pull water up, or there are several serious missing building interior materials. As usual, there probably wasn’t a problem on paper.</p> <p>On the other hand, in the communist system, it was a concept of renting from the state, not owning real estate, so it was a concept of applying for an apartment and renting it in the Soviet era. With Estonia’s independence from the Soviet Union in 1991, the places where the inhabitants lived were said to have been converted to their own. However, existing residents who owned real estate at the time of communism were treated as bourgeoisie or rich farmers and were taken to Siberia or executed, and their real estate was converted to state ownership, so such assets became an issue. It is said that some work was carried out to return the real estate that was unfairly taken by their descendants. However, it is said that only part of the record is made because it is not easy to find and prove the long-standing record of the country that has now disappeared on paper. The situation is very different, but it reminds me of Korea’s return of pro-Japanese property rights.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="trip"/><category term="history"/><category term="culture"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[what I could see and feel in Tallinn, Estonia]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My trip to Warsaw</title><link href="https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/trip-in-Warsaw/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My trip to Warsaw"/><published>2023-06-12T19:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-12T19:53:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/trip-in-Warsaw</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/trip-in-Warsaw/"><![CDATA[<p>What is the representative architecture of Warsaw, Poland. The Old Town of Warsaw does not look like something really old. It’s an old design, but it won’t give you an old feeling. Warsaw is a city directly destroyed by World War II, probably because most of its buildings have been collapsed and rebuilt.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-1-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-1-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-1-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/warsaw-1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Pałac Kulturyi Nauki (PKiN) at night with the red light. </div> <p>Figure 1. One of the representative buildings that comes to mind when you think of Warsaw, the Pałac Kulturyi Nauki (PKiN), is a tragic building that makes Polish people feel complicated. It is said that the building was built as a gift by Stalin, who forcibly communized Poland after World War II. In fact, it is so large (237m) that it is said that a building taller than this building was built in Warsaw only recently. This Stalin-style building can also be seen in Moscow, and its design gives people a sense of supression, not just its size.</p> <p>After the collapse of the Soviet Union, Poland immediately abandoned the communist system. Considering the humiliating things that the Soviet Union did to Poland, it may be deserved to blow it up like the Japanese Government-General of Korea, but as I mentioned before, it is too large a building. It’s such a big building that I can see well, so whenever I saw this building while walking around the streets of Warsaw, I thought about the Polish history.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-2-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-2-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-2-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/warsaw-2.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Józef Poniatowski statue in front of the presidential palace. </div> <p>Figure 2. Poland had a glorious era during a Polish-Lithuanian Grand Duchy. After the kingdom’s collapse, it has actually only gone downhill. Even if the results were not good, there should be respect for the bravery of the Poles in the process. There were statues of various historical figures around Warsaw Old Town, but I felt that Józef Poniatowski in front of the presidential palace was a good representation of Polish history. Many nobles were irresponsible of the crisis in their motherland, but many Poles fought bravely against the crisis in their mother country. Poniatowski stepped up and fought valiantly at every crisis in his country. He also served in the French army to regain his country and rose to one of the 26 French Marshal of Napoleon. It is said that he died in the final rush in the battlefield, which became disadvantageous even though he was brave and competent. And the situation in Poland continued to be bad, as Napoleon, who was favorable to Poland, fell.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-3-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-3-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/warsaw-3-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/warsaw-3.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Sign of Warsaw citizens during the uprising. </div> <p>Figure 3. The Warsaw Uprising Museum is recommended as a place to see the Polish spirit. Keeping in mind the response of the Soviet Red Army, which finally arrived in front of Warsaw in the late World War II, the Warsaw people uprised bravely against the occupied Nazi army, many of which were unarmed, but failed with numerous casualties. But the Poles built an uprising museum to remember their courage and spirit. The photo shows a sign worn by Warsaw citizens who participated in the uprising at the time.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay"/><category term="trip"/><category term="history"/><category term="culture"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[what I could see and feel in Warsaw, Poland]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My experience in the Korean military</title><link href="https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/militray-duty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My experience in the Korean military"/><published>2023-05-31T05:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-31T05:53:00+00:00</updated><id>https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/militray-duty</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shlee-lab.github.io/blog/2023/militray-duty/"><![CDATA[<p>To be written.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 480px)" srcset="/assets/img/mil-1-480.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 800px)" srcset="/assets/img/mil-1-800.webp"/> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" media="(max-width: 1400px)" srcset="/assets/img/mil-1-1400.webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/mil-1.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" data-zoomable="" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> Picture taken right before discharge. </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay"/><category term="military"/><category term="experience"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[what I could see and feel in the Korean military as an officer]]></summary></entry></feed>